Polish American Historical Association records 1932-2005 CPAA 05-11
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain
Polish American Historical Association records
1932-2005
Polish American Historical Association
CPAA 05-11
11 boxes (10.5 linear ft.)
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University
The Polish American Historical Association (PAHA) was established in 1942 to promote the study of immigration of Poles to the United States. For the first presidents of the organization it was important to promote scholarly knowledge of Poles and Polish Americans, collect and preserve information on the topic, and elevate historical research. PAHA attracted many scholars, secular and clergy, in the fields of history and ethnic studies. The organization promoted their mission through publication of the Polish American Studies journal. The collection consists of material documenting history of the organization and its various activities. It includes correspondence material from annual meetings and conferences as well as membership and financial data.
Historical/Biographical Note
PAHA was initially a part of the Polish Institute of Arts and Science (PIASA), which was organized in 1942 with the financial help of the Polish government, by Polish scholars and scientists who found refuge in the United States. The PIASA first president, Prof. Oskar Halecki, recognized the importance of studying immigration of Poles to America. In 1942 the Commission for Research on Polish Immigration was established and was led by Miecislaus Haiman, a published historian of Polonia. In 1944 the Commission became an independent organization devoted to the study and research of history of Polish Americans, and in 1948 adopted its current name - Polish American Historical Association.
Prof. Haiman realized how important it was to bring scholarly knowledge of Polish Americans to main stream history of America well before the movement of ethnic studies in late 1960's. Haiman’s priorities were raising the standards of historical research, advocating the importance of data collection and preservation and creating the proper archives for collected material. This agenda was upheld by Rev. Jospeh Swastek who was PAHA's second president. Among early members of PAHA there were many Catholic priests and nuns. Clergy played a very important role for immigrants and the church was the main institution that served spiritual needs as well as social and educational needs. For many immigrants, to become a priest or nun was a way to be educated. Later, second and third generations of Polish Americans interested in their own roots joined PAHA. They established several Polish Studies programs at American universities, pursued research projects related to Polish Americans and cooperated with scholars from Poland who were interested in the history of Polonia [as the Polish American community calls itself]. As a result of such interest a first joint conference was held in Krakow, Poland in 1986. In June of 2004 PAHA held their international conference at Central Connecticut State University in celebration of "150 years of Polonia in North America." Since 1944 PAHA has been publishing Polish American Studies, a journal which serves as a forum for scholars to share their research. It includes reviews, bibliographies, criticisms and information on future publications. PAHA publishes a quarterly newsletter for its members and organizes annual conferences, which take place during annual meetings of the American Historical Association (AHA), of which PAHA is an affiliate. PAHA funds some scholarly publications and gives several awards. The Haiman Award is for sustained effort in the area of Polish American Studies, the Halecki Prize is for the best book related to Polish American topic and the Swastek Prize is for the best scholarly article in Polish American Studies journal.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The PAHA archives consist of material related to establishing of the association, their constitution and by-laws and amendments. It includes material from conferences, executive directors' meetings and extensive correspondence with well known scholars in the field. Material includes information on membership, finances, various publications and extensive collection of clippings and documentation for various projects. The collection is chiefly in English with very small percentage of material in the Polish language.
The collection is open for research.
The PAHA archives were donated in 2005. Parts of the records were sent by presidents of the organization and periodicaly are sent by the executive secretary.
Search Terms
Polish American Historical Association.; Polish American Historical Associaiton -- Periodicals.; Correspondence.; Pamphlets.; Photographs.; Clippings.
Related Material
For related material see the following collections:
James S. Pula papers, CPAA 06-06
Stanislaus A. Blejwas collection, CPAA 86-14
Thaddeus Gromada papers, CPAA 06-04
PAHA website at http://www.polishamericanstudies.org/
Arrangement
Material in the collection is arranged in series. Folders within each series are in subject and chronological order. Boxes 8 and 9 contain correspondence and other related material compiled and bound by Walter Lasinski, Treasurer of PAHA for 1989-1992. The material is preserved in the form it was received, some items in the bound volumes might be duplicates of material already in the collection.
Series I Conference materials
Series II Mambership
Series III Financial material
Series IV Correspondence
Series V General
Container List
[The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.]
- Series I: Conference materials., 1943-2004
  - PAHA Conference, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - PAHA Conference, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - PAHA Conference, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - PAHA Conference, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - PAHA Conference, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - PAHA Conference, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - PAHA Conference, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - PAHA Conference, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - PAHA Conference, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - PAHA Conference, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - PAHA Conference, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - PAHA Conference, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - PAHA Conference, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - PAHA Conference, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - PAHA Conference, 1957, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - PAHA Conference, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - PAHA Conference, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - PAHA Conference, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - PAHA Conference, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - PAHA Conference, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - PAHA Conference, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - PAHA Conference, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - PAHA Conference, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - PAHA Conference, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - PAHA Conference, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - PAHA Conference, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - PAHA Conference, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - PAHA Conference, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - PAHA Conference, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - PAHA Conference, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - PAHA Conference, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - PAHA Conference, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - PAHA Conference, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - PAHA Conference, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - PAHA Conference, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - PAHA Conference, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - PAHA Conference, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - PAHA Conference, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - PAHA Conference, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - PAHA Conference, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - PAHA Conference, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - PAHA Conference, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - PAHA Conference, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - PAHA Conference, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - PAHA Conference, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - PAHA Conference, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - PAHA Conference, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - PAHA Conference, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - PAHA Conference, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - PAHA Conference, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - PAHA Conference, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - PAHA Conference, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - PAHA Conference, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - PAHA Conference, registration material, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - PAHA Conference, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - PAHA Conference, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - PAHA Conference, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 11A)
  - PAHA Conference, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - PAHA Conference, board meeting, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - PAHA Conference, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - PAHA Conference and mid-year meeting on CD, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 14A)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - PAHA Mid-year meeting, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 39A)
  - PAHA Constitution, [undated] (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - PAHA Constitution, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - PAHA Constitution for local chapters, [1970's] (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - PAHA Constitution for local chapters and by-laws, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Series II: Membership
  - PAHA Membership, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - PAHA Membership, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - PAHA Membership, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - PAHA Membership, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - PAHA Membership, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - PAHA Membership, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - PAHA Membership, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - PAHA Membership, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - PAHA Membership, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - PAHA Membership, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - PAHA Membership, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - PAHA Membership, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - PAHA Membership, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - PAHA Membership, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - PAHA Membership, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - PAHA Membership, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - PAHA Membership, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - PAHA Membership, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - PAHA Membership, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - PAHA Membership, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - PAHA Membership, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - PAHA Membership, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - PAHA Membership, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - PAHA Membership, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - PAHA Membership, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - PAHA Membership, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - PAHA Membership, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - PAHA Membership, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - PAHA Membership, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - PAHA Membership drive project, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - PAHA Membership drive project, 1999-2004 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - PAHA Membership drive project - Polish National Catholic Church, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - PAHA Membership, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - PAHA Awards, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - PAHA Awards, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - PAHA Awards, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - PAHA Awards, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - PAHA Awards, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - PAHA Awards, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - PAHA Awards, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - PAHA Awards, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - PAHA Awards, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - PAHA Awards, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - PAHA Awards, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - PAHA Awards, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - PAHA Awards, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - PAHA Awards, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - PAHA Awards, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - PAHA Awards, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - PAHA Awards, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - PAHA Awards, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - PAHA Awards, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - PAHA Elections, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - PAHA Elections, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - PAHA Elections, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - PAHA Elections, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - PAHA Elections, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - PAHA Elections, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - PAHA Elections, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - PAHA Elections, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - PAHA Elections, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - PAHA Elections, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - PAHA Elections, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - PAHA Elections, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - PAHA Elections, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - PAHA Elections, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - PAHA Elections, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - PAHA Elections, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - PAHA Elections, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - PAHA Elections, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - PAHA Elections, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - PAHA Elections, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Series III: Financial material
  - PAHA Finances, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PAHA Finances, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PAHA Finances, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - PAHA Finances, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - PAHA Finances, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - PAHA Finances, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - PAHA Finances, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - PAHA Finances, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - PAHA Finances, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - PAHA Finances, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - PAHA Finances, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - PAHA Finances, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - PAHA Finances, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - PAHA Finances, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - PAHA Finances, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - PAHA Finances, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - PAHA Finances, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - PAHA Finances, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - PAHA Finances, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - PAHA Finances, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - PAHA Finances, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - PAHA Finances, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - PAHA Finances, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - PAHA Finances, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - PAHA Finances, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - PAHA Finances, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - PAHA Finances, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - PAHA Finances, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - PAHA Finances, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - PAHA Finances, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - PAHA Finances, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - PAHA treasurer correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - PAHA petty cash, 2000-2002 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - PAHA tax exemptions, IRS, 1972-1995 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - PAHA Scholarship awards, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - PAHA registration for Incorporation, 1963, 1996-2003 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - PAHA Tax exempt status, 1978-1986 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Series IV: Correspondence
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - PAHA Correspondence, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - PAHA Joseph Wieczerzak correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - PAHA Joseph Wieczerzak correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - PAHA Joseph Wieczerzak correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - PAHA Joseph Wieczerzak correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Joseph Wieczerzak, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Albin Wozniak, 1977, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Anthony Turhollow, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Reverend Wojciech Sojka, 1980, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Alfred Sokolnicki, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Leszek Szymanski, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Edward Skenzel, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with George Lerski, 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Frank Renkiewicz, 1972-1983 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with James Pula, 1977, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Sister Mary Flugenta Piasecki, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Rev. Jacek Przygoda, 1972-1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Angela Pienkos, 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Bernardine Pietraszek, 1970-1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Eugene Obidinski, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Thomas Napierkowski, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Rev. M.J. Madaj, 1971-1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Rev. M.J. Madaj, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Mark Kulikowski, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Rev. Anthony Kuzniewski, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Sister Clarent Marie, 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Sister Clarent Marie, 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Regina Koscielski, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Rev. Anthony Iwuc, 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Sister Mary Serafina Gacek, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - PAHA Letters to Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki from Prof. Walter Drzewieniecki, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Raymond Dziedzic, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Eugene Dziedzic, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Wanda Cytowska, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Stanley Cuba, 1978-1983 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with John J. Bukowczyk, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Andrzej Brozek, 1979-1984 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Metchie Budka, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Daniel Buczek, 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Stanislaus A. Blejwas, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Jadwiga Bogucki, 1974-1978 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Rev. Donald Bilinski, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Lindsay Baker, 1978-1979, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - PAHA correspondence Sister Ellen Marie Kuznicki with Joseph Alecks, 1978, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - PAHA correspondence with Polish American Congress, 1972-1997 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - PAHA miscellaneous correspondence, 1980-1986 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - PAHA correspondence - Stanislaus A. Blejwas, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - PAHA correspondence - Anthony Bukoski, 1997-2002 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - PAHA correspondence - John Bukowczyk, 1998-2003 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - PAHA correspondence - Mary Cygan, 1998-2008 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - PAHA correspondence - Mary Erdmans, 1995-2005 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - PAHA correspondence - William Galush, 1998-2002 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - PAHA correspondence - Thomas Gladsky, 1999-2002 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - PAHA correspondence - Victor Greene, 1997-2002 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - PAHA correspondence - Thaddeus Gromada, 1998-2003 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - PAHA correspondence - Ann Gunkel, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - PAHA correspondence - Thomas Napierkowski, 1997-2002 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - PAHA correspondence - Elzbieta Orlinska, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - PAHA correspondence - Donald Pienkos, 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - PAHA correspondence - James Pula, 2001-2003 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - PAHA correspondence - John Radzilowski, 1998-2002 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - PAHA General correspondence, William Galush, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - PAHA General correspondence - William Galush, January-June, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - PAHA General correspondence - William Galush, July-December, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - PAHA General correspondence - James Pula, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - PAHA General correspondence - James Pula, January-March, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - PAHA General correspondence - James Pula, April-December, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - PAHA General correspondence, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - PAHA General correspondence, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - PAHA General correspondence, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - PAHA General correspondence, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - PAHA General correspondence, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - PAHA General correspondence, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - PAHA Correspondence and related material to prof. Stanislaus A. Blejwas passing., 2001 (Box 7, Folder 12A)